// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question:
      "Two pipes A and B can fill a cistern in 6 and 8 minutes respectively. If A starts the work and they be turned on alternatively for one minute each, how long will it take to fill the cistern?",
    answer: "27/4 minutes",
    options: ["24/7 minutes", "27/4 minutes", "6 minutes", "48/7 minutes"],
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question:
      "A punctured tyre can deflate in 12 min. while a pumping machine takes 3 minutes to completely inflate a tyre. What will be the time taken to inflate the tyre when both the leak and pump are working together?",
    answer: "4 minutes",
    options: ["4 minutes", "5 minutes", "6 minutes", "8 minutes"],
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question:
      "Pipes P and Q can fill a storage tank in full with water in 10 and 6 minutes, respectively. Pipe R draws the water out from the storage tank at a rate of 34 litres per minute. P, Q and R operate at a constant rate. If it takes one hour to completely empty a full storage tank with all the pipes operating simultaneously, what is the capacity of the storage tank (in litres)?",
    answer: "120",
    options: ["26.8", "60", "120", "127.5"],
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question:
      "Pipe P & Pipe Q can fill a tank in 5 hours and 15 hours respectively. R can empty the same tank in 7.5 hours. How much time will all the three take together to fill the same tank?",
    answer: "7.5 hours",
    options: ["2.5 hours", "12.5 hours", "3.5 hours", "7.5 hours"],
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question:
      "Two pipes A and B can fill a tank in 12 and 24 minutes respectively. If both the pipes are used together, then how long will it take to fill the tank?",
    answer: "8 min",
    options: ["6 min", "4 min", "9 min", "8 min"],
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question:
      "TTwo inlet pipes A and B together can fill a tank in 24 min, and it takes 6 min more when one leak is developed in the tank. Find the time taken by leak alone to empty the tank.",
    answer: "2 hours",
    options: ["3 hours", "4 hours", "2.5 hours", "2 hours"],
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question:
      "Three flood gates A, B and C can fill a reservoir in 6 hours. After working at it together for 2 hours, flood gate C is closed. Flood gates A and B can fill the remaining part in 7 hours. The number of hours taken by flood gate C alone to fill the reservoir is:",
    answer: "14",
    options: ["16", "10", "14", "12"],
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question:
      "Pipes A and B can fill a tank with water in 30 minutes and 40 minutes, respectively, while pipe C can drain off 51 litres of water per minute. If all the three pipes are opened together, the tank is filled in 90 minutes. What is the capacity (in litres) of the tank?",
    answer: "1080",
    options: ["900", "864", "720", "1080"],
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question:
      "Two pipes A and B together can fill a tank in 6 hours. If pipe A can fill 5 hours faster than pipe B, in how many hours pipe B alone can fill the tank?",
    answer: "15",
    options: ["12", "10", "18", "15"],
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question:
      "A tap can fill a tank in 8 hrs. After half the tank is filled, three more similar taps are opened. What is the total time taken to fill the tank completely?",
    answer: "5 hrs",
    options: [
      "6 hrs",
      "5 hrs",
      "3 hrs",
      "4 hrs",
    ],
  },
];
